In your casa, the internet never stops.
Neither does Optimum.
While 5G home internet slows down when your vecinos log on,
Optimum keeps going.
Bueno.
Famously fast, fiber internet.
Bonito.
Whole home coverage.
Evry rincón, barato.
Smart value.
Your familia will love.
Get Optimum fiber internet for only $30 a month
with a five-year price lock.
Bueno.
Bonito.
Barato.
Three words your familia already knows.
Don't settle.
Go 3B with Optimum.
Call 888 for Optimum.
Or visit optimum.com slash 3B to switch today.
Terms applies.
The Optimum.com for details.
Big color.
Bigger savings.
Sherwin-Williams Super Sale is here.
Get 40% off paints and stains.
August 7th through the 13th.
With prices starting at $30.89.
Whether you're refreshing your interior or exterior,
we've got the colors to bring your vision to life.
And with delivery, getting everything to your door
is easier than ever.
Shop online to have it delivered
or visit your neighborhood Sherwin-Williams store.
Click the banner to learn more.
Retail sales only.
Custom exclusions apply.
C-Star for details.
Delivery available on qualifying orders.
And as we're driving, we see this brilliant flash
of white light.
And we both looked up into the sky.
And there's a second flash and then a third flash.
And then this orange trapezoid lit up
and just hovered in the sky.
And if you're a wixoblower, you have rights.
I would also recommend very strongly
that you seek the assistance of an attorney
before blowing the whistle.
Not after.
That's the mistake that I made.
I had to be reactive to everything the government was doing.
I thought, well, I'm not the only person
who's opposed to this.
So somebody's going to say something.
And then nobody said anything.
And so finally I said something.
And the government fell on top of my head.
So I ended up going to prison for 23 months.
I have zero regrets.
I would do it again tomorrow.
I think we would be fools if we didn't have a retrieval program.
And of course, because of its very nature,
it would have to be classified at the very highest levels.
Nobody's asking the government to release the details.
Just put our minds at ease that we're not crazy
when we see these things in the sky.
And then you say, no, you didn't.
You didn't see anything.
Chris Lado, welcome to Lado Files.
Hi, welcome to Lado Files.
I have a very exciting guest today.
I'm with John Kiriakou.
He's a former CIA officer, whistleblower and author
who exposed the US government's use of torture
in its counterterrorism operations.
As a veteran intelligence officer,
he played a key role in capturing high-profile al-Qaeda members
before becoming the first US official
to publicly confirm the CIA's waterboarding practices.
His revelations led to significant public debate
on ethics in intelligence and government accountability,
ultimately resulting in his own prosecution.
Today's an advocate for whistleblower rights.
He's a journalist.
He has a show, CIA declassified,
and he's a vocal critic of governmental overreach.
Thank you, John, for being here.
How are you doing today, sir?
Thanks for having me.
Doing well, thanks.
Okay, amazing.
I was happy to be on your CIA declassified show.
We'll show a teaser later on in the show.
But on that, you explained about your own personal UAP experience.
Can you tell us about that?
My audience would love to hear it.
Sure.
When I was 17 years old,
my mom and dad bought a restaurant in a nearby town.
We lived in Newcastle, Pennsylvania,
which is about an hour north of Pittsburgh.
It's a very rural area.
They bought a restaurant in Sharon, Pennsylvania.
It was 20 miles away.
And so to get from Newcastle to Sharon,
you have to drive through Amish country.
And it's very, very dark in Amish country
because the Amish don't use any electricity.
So my dad and I, on the weekends, worked the midnight shift.
I was a short order cook,
and of course he was there to manage the restaurant.
So we left our house on a Friday night.
It was at 10 o'clock.
Figure we'll get there at 10 30 to start working at 11.
And we're in Amish country, very, very dark again.
And as we're driving,
we see this brilliant flash of white light.
And we both looked up into the sky
and there's a second flash and then a third flash.
And then this orange trapezoid lit up
and just hovered in the sky.
We pulled the car over and got out.
So the thing hovered there for long enough
for us to get out of the car.
And we're standing there just staring at it.
Without saying anything,
a man pulls up behind us and gets out and he says,
what the heck is that?
And my dad said, I don't know.
And then it just took off at a fantastic speed.
Unlike anything I've seen,
or I had seen before or have seen since,
I mean, it just, it went like that.
Fantastic speed.
And we just stood there looking in the sky.
And then we got back into the car,
started driving again.
And I said to my father,
should we call somebody?
Should we like call the cops or something?
And he said to say what,
we saw UFO and it flew away.
People will think we're crazy.
And so we didn't say anything.
I told my mom the next morning.
She believed us, of course.
My dad said exactly the same thing that I did.
And I'll tell you, for weeks after that,
my eyes were just glued into the night sky,
hoping that I could see it again or something again.
And that was, you know, 43 years ago.
And I've never seen anything like that since.
That's an amazing story.
And you said no sound, right?
No sound at all.
And it just hovered.
And it wasn't terribly far away.
I'm going to say it was hovering at,
I don't know, 2,000 feet,
3,000 feet, maybe 3,000 feet.
And not making any sound at all,
just hovering there.
And I should add too.
So it's in this trapezoidal,
my fingers can't do it,
trapezoidal shape.
And in the four corners of it were bright glowing orange lights
to the point where the orange lights were so bright
that they illuminated the rest of whatever it was.
And you know, over the years I've said to myself,
maybe it was a balloon.
No, of course it's not a balloon
because of the speed with which it took off like that.
And it wasn't just floating there
and then it just kind of casually floated away
like a balloon might.
There's a small municipal airport.
Oh, just three or four miles away.
But it closes at sunset.
And so it wasn't that.
And I honestly,
I don't have any explanation for what it was
other than it was unexplained.
Any idea how large it was or how big it was?
I know it's hard to tell at distance.
Yeah, hard to tell, but I'm going to say
I'm going to say it was probably 25 or 30 feet across.
Big, bigger than, you know, a Cessna.
It was at that airport that I learned to fly years later.
So comparing it to a Cessna.
Yeah, it was two or three, two and a half, three times the size.
Did you talk to your father later on,
like later in your life about it?
Yeah, I sure did.
But it was always one of us saying,
remember that thing we saw up in the sky back in in 82?
Like, well, how can I forget that thing we saw up in the sky in 82?
Yeah, I remember it.
And then, you know, because I had seen something,
I immediately took an interest.
And as I mentioned to you on, on the CIA to classified,
Jimmy Carter saw something that was unexplained and went so far
as to file a police report saying that he had seen this
thing hovering in the sky.
But he said that what he saw was buzzing.
He admitted a buzz that he could hear.
But if the president of the United States is seeing, you know,
things in the sky, then, you know, I don't feel so alone.
Yeah.
When, when is the first time you actually talked about it?
Did you feel the stigma?
You know, did you feel a need to keep quiet about this?
I did.
I did because I didn't,
I didn't want people to think I was crazy or making something up.
And I tell you what, over the years I've,
I've thought about it and I've, I've thought, you know,
my goodness, my dad was there and my dad saw it because my father
was, you know, this seriously a pillar of the community.
When he died, it was on the front page of the local paper.
He was that kind of a pillar of the community.
And so if Chris Kiriakou saw it, then something was up there.
And did he ever talk about it?
No.
Publicly.
No, never.
Just to me.
And like I say, it was, it was always remember that thing we saw up in
the sky in 82.
Yeah.
Have you seen anything since then?
No, nothing even remotely close.
But I've mentioned this a couple of times to friends, close friends
and relatives.
And I've been surprised at how many people have seen things that
they just have not been able to explain.
I mentioned to you on CIA to classified that I'm very close to
a, to a cousin, a second cousin.
He's older than I am 14, 15 years older than I am.
And his father owned a restaurant too here in, in Alexandria,
Virginia.
And so when I was a kid, I used to come down here, stay with
them, hang out at the restaurant.
And he had a friend who was an Air Force pilot.
And he told me once that he saw something, some sort of
craft dive straight down into the water.
Off the coast of Virginia Beach, Virginia.
And then seconds later come straight up out of the water and
fly away.
And I said, what in the world do you think that was?
And he said, we're not supposed to use the words flying saucer,
but it looked like a flying saucer going down to get a drink.
That's what it looked like.
And that's always stuck with me as well.
And again, this isn't just some nut that you sit next to
in a bar.
This is an Air Force pilot, a fighter pilot, right?
These are the best of the best.
They're the guys who have gone through the most extensive
training and, you know, to be able to handle a craft like
that.
And if he says that he saw something like that, I believe
him.
It's interesting too because the coast of Virginia,
that's basically where Ryan Graves, you know, his
four ship video, the gimbal.
That's right.
UAP video.
And they've seen many other sightings.
They said almost daily sightings of these strange objects,
you know, a dark cube inside of a sphere, some sort of
clear sphere.
So it's interesting off the coast of Virginia.
And, you know, it makes me think too, whatever these
are, do they congregate around air bases?
Or is it because we have air bases and we have
pilots and people trained in this kind of thing that we
see them there more frequently?
I'm not sure.
I think, yeah, we don't know, you know, because the
data certainly comes from where our military aircraft
are flying, or at least from Aero, you know, the data
they released was basically all of our training areas.
So it could be where we're looking.
Maybe that's why our nuclear sites have so much
surveillance.
You know, maybe that's why we're seeing them or
our military aircraft are out there actually seeing
these things.
It could be, I guess, everywhere, but we're just not
looking in those areas.
I don't know.
It's an interesting question.
I was amazed to see or to hear the conversations
between pilots either released or leaked a year or
two years ago, where, you know, they're saying
things like, are you seeing this?
What is that?
And they're watching these things take off at these
amazing speeds, speeds that we're just not capable
of doing.
So you've been interested in UAPs since your own
sighting?
Or have you just thought of it recently?
No, since my own sighting.
And like I say, I've looked at the skies ever
since.
I'm a lifelong, well, not lifelong, but since
then.
Telescope user.
I have started doing astrophotography.
The skies fascinate me.
And I so wish I had seen something a second time,
just to sort of reinforce my own belief that there
really was something out there.
But I've never seen it again.
When you were in the CIA for many years, did you
ever hear anything about UFOs or UAPs?
Because in the Air Force, my whole career, I'd never
heard anything.
No, not a single word.
And when I joined the CIA in 1990, we had just
initiated this transition from paper documents to
computers.
I'm going to date myself here.
I don't feel very old.
But when I joined the CIA, we had typewriters
on our desks.
And you could smoke at your desk as crazy as
that is.
Oh, and even crazier.
There was a barbershop in the basement of the
CIA.
And they had playboys out, right?
So this was a different era.
Yeah, it was a different era.
You can't do any of that stuff anymore.
But anyway, we started to transition to electronic
systems.
And virtually as soon as I arrived, I said only
half jokingly.
So where's the UFO information kept?
And my boss laughed.
He said, we all ask that when we get here.
There is nothing like that.
If there is such a thing, it's with the Pentagon.
And that was always my understanding because I never,
ever, ever saw anything related to these kind of
phenomena.
Yeah, the same.
I remember I was an aggressor in Alaska, actually,
but that's when we were flying those cool painted
airplanes.
And we got to take a trip to the CIA.
I'll never forget it.
You know, we walked through the long entrance,
you know, the white tunnel entrance.
And the big deal was it was the highest classified
lunch room we'd ever been in.
You know, we're eating lunch in this top secret lunch
room.
That was like the highlight of going to visit the CIA.
Yeah.
Even the fast food people have security clearances.
We used to have two different lunch rooms.
There was the classified cafeteria and the unclassified
cafeteria.
The unclassified cafeteria was so tiny.
Nobody even bothered to go there.
And it was on, it was for use during those rare
occasions when somebody, it was usually a government
worker from some other department or agency,
but who didn't have a security clearance came for
lunch.
And then they just did away with it because nobody
was using it.
So now you have to be clear to get into the
cafeteria because half the people in there are
undercover.
So you can't, you know.
In your casa, the internet never stops.
Neither does Optimum.
While 5G home internet slows down when your
vecinos log on, Optimum keeps going.
Bueno.
Famously fast fiber internet.
Bonito.
Whole home coverage.
Every rincón, barato.
Smart value.
Your family will love.
Get Optimum fiber internet for only $30 a month
with a five-year price lock.
Bueno.
Bonito.
Barato.
Three words your family already knows.
Don't settle.
Go 3B with Optimum.
Call 888-4-Optimum or visit
optimum.com slash 3B to switch today.
Terms apply.
See Optimum.com for details.
You can't just have somebody off the street.
Yeah, it was funny.
That was the highlight was the lunch room for
us.
The classified lunch room.
But I mean, it really is amazing.
You know, you came out as a whistleblower
against waterboarding against our
government doing what I think many
people would consider as, you know, evil
things, torturing people to get
information and keeping it secret.
So I think it's very courageous for
whistleblowers such as yourself to
come out.
So thank you for doing that.
And can you give us some background?
What was that experience like?
It was, it was rough.
I was the, I was the chief of CIA
counterterrorism operations in Pakistan
after the 9-11 attacks.
And we, we carried out raids, dozens
upon dozens of raids.
And we caught a man by the name of
Abu Zubaydah who we believed was the
number three in Al Qaeda at the time.
I objected almost
immediately to the treatment
that we were, that we were using
on prisoners
before we began torturing Abu Zubaydah.
For example, the night that we
captured Abu Zubaydah, we caught
dozens of Al Qaeda fighters.
I'm still not allowed to say the
number of Al Qaeda fighters that we
caught. And this is a minor
point, but it, it's sort of
indicative of, of the way things
ended up going.
We caught so many people that
night that we had to bring them
out for interrogation in shifts.
And there was
an idiot working for me
and he led this group of
ten prisoners in
and they had hoods on.
And I said,
why are they hooded?
And he said, we don't want them to
see our faces.
And I said, are you seriously
telling me that you have never
read the Geneva Convention?
It is a war crime to put
seriously. I said, take the
hoods off. And
he said, wait a minute. He tells his
the other these other guys that
were standing there. He said, wait a
minute. If you take the hoods off, I'm
going to report you to headquarters. And I said, oh,
I'm already reporting you to headquarters
for committing a war crime.
Take the hoods off. We took the hoods
off. We reported each other
and I got in trouble. You got in
trouble. I got in trouble.
I said, it is a war
crime to hood prisoners.
And headquarters
senior officer at headquarters told me
that the world has
changed since 9 11.
We do things our way.
And I said, but the Constitution
hasn't changed.
You know, behind my back, they started
calling me the human rights guy.
And I didn't care. And then a friend
of mine, I have this good friend.
He's he's a lot of things. He's a renaissance
man. He's a Brigadier General in the
Army Reserve. He's a psychiatrist at the
CIA Brigadier General in the Army Reserve.
He's a psychiatrist at the CIA.
We've got to the same church. We're in the same
men's group. So he came up to me one day
and he said, you know, they call you
the human rights guy behind your back.
And I said, I know, I don't care.
And he said, you know, that's not
a compliment.
And I said, Steve, I'm right
and they're wrong.
And I don't care if they're insulting
me. Well,
this torture program
was so patently illegal
in my mind
that
there was never any question
about it. We have
the Federal Torture Act
of 1946, which forbids exactly
those techniques that we
used. We are not just
signatories to, but we're the
authors of the United Nations
Convention Against Torture,
right, which specifically
bans. We wrote the
we wrote it. We wrote the International
Treaty, which has
of course the force of law in the United
States. And then
we just decided that we're going to
do it anyway. And we did it anyway.
It was so patently illegal that I
just assumed somebody
would come forward
and blow the whistle on it. And I'm
seeing these highly classified cables
where people are saying, well,
wait a minute. You know, when I took
Democratic oath, I swore
to do no harm. And now you want
me to torture this guy or
revive him so he can be tortured
more. And I resigned
or I'm curtailing my torn. I'm coming
back to Washington. So I thought, well,
I'm not the only person
who's opposed to this. So somebody
is going to say something. And then nobody said
anything. And so finally,
finally, I said something
and the government
fell on top of my head.
So I ended up
going to prison for 23 months.
I have zero regrets.
I would do it again
tomorrow. And
in the end
John McCain, thank God for John
McCain and Dianne Feinstein
passed the McCain-Feinstein
amendment, which
formally banned
torture. It was signed into law
in December of
2014 and
2016.
The Internet never stops.
Neither does Optimum. While 5G Home
Internet slows down when your
vecinos log on, Optimum keeps going.
Famously fast, Fiber Internet.
Bonito. Whole home coverage.
Every rincón, barato. Smart value.
Your family will love. Get Optimum Fiber
Internet for only $30 a month with
a five-year price lock.
Bonito. Barato. Three words your
family already knows. Don't settle. Go
3B with Optimum. Call
the four to 12 and
you get an option to apply.
The Optimum. Comfort details.
You know, the price was high, but we
did it.
It sounds like
torture is not even going to give
you good intel.
Even at the end of the day.
You can always say I'm being tortured.
Exactly.
And the fallout from that is
several cold.
None of the al-Qaeda leadership
have been prosecuted because
Nothing that they said can be used
and second
The information just isn't reliable. Is the person going to tell you what you want to know?
Probably, but he's going to give you so much trash to go with it
Yeah, that it's going to take your teams of analysts six months to go through it to decide or to determine
What's true and what's not true and by then, you know, the bomb has gone off or the next attack has taken place and
It ends up netting you nothing nothing
Besides the fact that you've put yourself on the same moral plane that they're on I know it's amazing to me
It seems like all of this just comes from fear
Like you mentioned they're willing to break the law because they're scared of their faces being shown
You know, they're willing to let their integrity just be trampled or to look the other way
Because of it's a fear, right? Basically. Yeah
We even had there there were two FBI translators that were on loan to us that night that we did the raids and
We carry out the raids. It's you know, three three thirty in the morning and the translators said
I I don't want to translate. It's like, what do you mean? You don't want to translate?
Well, I don't want them to see my face
well, then maybe you should have gone into another line of work and
So I ended up doing the translations. It was ridiculous
Yeah, well, they have to have woods. No, they have to not have woods because it's a violation of the Geneva Convention
Yeah, it's amazing and
And the fact that no one else went along with it, you know when you reported them and
Then you got in trouble even though you knew without a doubt you knew the law
You knew the rules. You knew that we're not, you know laws of armed conflict. Obviously we follow those we wrote them
So I guess how did you feel when you when you were attacked as you were reporting what is correct?
Well, you know that the initial the initial feeling is one of extreme disappointment
But the day after I blew the whistle. I got an email
From a retired deputy director of the CIA someone for whom I had long-standing respect and
He said to me you've chosen a difficult road
But somebody had to say something. I only wish I had had the guts to do it myself
And that meant so much to me. I saved it all these years
That it made me realize that I wasn't alone. There weren't gonna be people
There weren't gonna be very many people to stand up for me in public. There were some
But I knew deep down that I wasn't alone
And we're taught that you know, I mean I remember at the Air Force Academy just you know crawling through the mud
Having people yell at you. You're so tired. You're exhausted and they just beat it into you that you know
All you really have at the end of the day is your integrity. That's it
You know, that's it. Let's so now even though you did 23 months in prison for this
You would gladly do it again, you know, it just shows that it does matter integrity is is important
Absolutely, I would do it again. Yeah, the first the first interview that I gave when I got out of prison was was to the BBC
the British Broadcasting Corporation and they have a they have a program called
hard talk and it's supposed to be like
It's considered to be sort of the 60 minutes of of the UK, but it's very very
Confrontational where they will yell and scream and point the finger at you and they want to provoke a fight and so I
Just wasn't
playing the game and
They finally the interviewer says you're not showing any remorse at all for your crime
And I said I said no
Because I have no remorse. I would do it again today if I had the opportunity. I would do it again
I'm not making any apologies for anything. I was right and they were wrong and history will smile on me
So no, I show no remorse and then afterwards
Oh, and then there was a second question that he asked that he kind of got angry that I didn't respond to
He said you don't appear to have any hostility to the people who put you in prison
And I said no, I actually don't because what would that gain for me?
right if if Nelson Mandela can can forgive the the apartheid government for imprisoning him for decades or
Martin Luther King can can forgive the people who imprisoned him dozens of times for standing up for his rights
I have no right to be angry for being imprisoned. And so it doesn't I don't gain anything by being angry
Or bitter it's water under the bridge and as soon as I said water under the bridge
He said I find that very hard to believe and I said, well, I'm sorry that that you're angry that I'm not angry
But I'm not angry and to tell you the truth things have worked out very nicely for me
You know the country has come around to my point of view
John McCain stood up on the floor of the Senate and said that that without my revelations
the American people would never have had any idea what the CIA was doing in their name and
so
You know you get to know who your friends are your real friends and
And who walks away from you which was also very valuable. So it was all worth it
It's amazing and
Yeah, so you were able to forgive them. Have you seen the system change?
What is your feeling on the the recent whistleblowers that come out and say that their lives have been threatened?
You know like David Grush, they did freedom of information act request on a random
Sheriff location to find out issues about his home life as PTSD issues. What's your take on these current whistleblowers?
Yeah, that's that's scandalous
there's
First of all, I just as a policy I support all whistleblowers. There's a legal definition of whistleblowing
It is bringing to light any evidence of waste fraud abuse
Illegality or threats to the public health or public safety
So if you've done that you're a whistleblower and if you're a whistleblower you have rights
I would also recommend very strongly that you seek the assistance of an attorney
Before blowing the whistle not after that's the mistake that I made
I had to be reactive to everything the government was doing
So if you're thinking of blowing the whistle hire an attorney
First and have that attorney sitting next to you when you blow the whistle
But what you're talking about is is actually a very common kind of harassment that whistleblowers face
The the other side immediately tries to discredit you. Oh, he has PTSD
Oh, he saw you know a marriage counselor 10 years ago. Oh, he's on an antidepressant
None of that is relevant to your whistleblowing
It's it either you told the truth or you didn't tell the truth
And if you told the truth
Everything that you said is protected by law
So everything is protected by law, but in your case you still went to jail
Is that because you didn't talk to a lawyer first or why do you think that happened? No, no
There's a book there's a book written by a Harvard law professor by the name of Harvey Silverglate called three felonies a day
And he says that we are so
Overly regulated so overly criminalized in our country
That the average American on the average day going about his or her normal business
Commits three felonies
Every single day
We have five percent of the world's population in the united states. We have 25 percent of the world's prison population
Yeah, so if they want to get you they're going to get you
They charged me with three counts of espionage for
For blowing the whistle on the torture program. I hadn't committed espionage
They offered me 45 years in prison
And and I said now and as a matter of fact
I'm going to go to trial and I'm going to testify on my own behalf
And I might accidentally talk about some of the heaviest crimes against humanity and war crimes that I witnessed in 15 years at the CIA
They ended up dropping all of the espionage charges, but then they charged me with this obscure law
Obscure crime. I was the only the second person ever charged with this crime in american history called the intelligence identities protection act
And um, it was because I had confirmed
The last name of a former co-worker
That's the crime
That's the crime and and the name was never made public
So how did you who did you confirm it to?
If it's not published a journalist a journalist writing a book
And he said hey, can you introduce me to this guy named john?
Uh, you used to work with him and I said, oh, I think you're talking about john doe
I said, I don't know whatever happened. He's probably retired living in virginia somewhere
In your casa the internet never stops neither does optimum
While 5g home internet slows down when your vecinos log on optimum keeps going
Bueno famously fast fiber internet bonito whole home coverage every rincón barato smart value
Your family will love get optimum fiber internet for only 30 dollars a month with a five-year price lock bueno bonito barato
Three words your family already knows don't settle go 3b with optimum call 888 for optimum or visit optimum dot com slash 3b to switch today
Terms applies the optimum dot com for details
That was the crime
That's it
They put you to they put you in prison for 23 months for that
They had to do something and they thought that was going to silence me see here. Here's the crux of the whole thing
They thought that was that would silence me and instead it made me a star
Now I am I'm known internationally as a human rights, uh, activist. I'm a I'm a journalist
I'm on tv constantly
You go to my IMDb page. It's over a hundred, uh tv appearances talking mostly about
torture and and the cia and and war crimes and things like that. I've written eight books
I've not only testified before the the european parliament
But but I wrote a whistleblower protection law for the greek government
That was then adopted by the european parliament and is now the law of the entire european union
They've they've made me they've made me what I am today
Just because they thought that prosecuting me
Would uh would silence me and instead it it made me somebody
Interesting
And I have to ask is he's obviously controversial. What is your take on edward snowden?
Well, I think I think snowden's a bona fide american hero
We we wouldn't have had any idea
That the government was spying on us if snowden hadn't said something and not only is it illegal
For the government to intercept our communications. It's a part of nsa's charter
That they're not permitted to spy on americans and in fact
Most of what they do is to spy on americans
Yeah, but we wouldn't have had any idea
It's amazing. Let me add something to that too if I could chris um
A couple of weeks ago
Tulsi gabbard
The the new director of national intelligence appeared before the senate intelligence committee as part of her confirmation hearings
and senators of both parties
repeatedly
Tried to get her to say ed snowden was a was a
trader
Both parties and they used the word trader over and over and over again. Well
either
these senators are stupid
Or they're
ill-informed
There is a constitutional definition of treason
And it is providing aid and comfort to the enemy in a time of war
He did not provide aid and comfort to the enemy and we are not in a time of war
There hasn't been a congressional declaration of war since
December the 8th 1941 the day after pearl harbor. Well, so
by definition
He's not a trader
secondly
senator angus king the independent democrat from maine
um
Tried to get tulsi
to say that
Snowden had defected to russia. This is something that he kept repeating. He had defected to russia. He did not defect to russia
He was in the transit lounge
At moscow airport on his way to ecuador
When john carrey the secretary of state
Uh revoked his passport and stranded him
In the transit lounge at moscow airport
So there was no defection to russia
And this nonsensical accusation that what he turned over to the russians
Uh what he took from nsa. No, he turned over to the washington post and the guardian and wiki leaks
What he took from nsa. It's all out there. Anybody can can go look at it
He didn't turn it over to the russians
It's there for any american to see
So these are just lies about snowden to try to trip up tulsi gabbert and it's a shame that it came
From both the left and the right from both the republicans and the democrats
Yeah, i'm very happy to hear you say that. Um
I was just so angry to learn about the nsa
Uh the program, you know really just spying on all of uh all of our data all americans
And I remember I make no excuses. Yeah, there's no excuses. They were found no they were found
uh, it was
In two federal courts it was found that what they were doing was incorrect and yet I yes if I mention anything about snowden on my channel
I mean from diehard patrons from, you know, long-term supporters will just write me angry messages
You know saying that he's a traitor
He's done all these things. I don't like the way he did it
And again, they attacked the person like he mentioned
They attack him
But what about the terrible misdeeds that our government was doing?
You know exactly those doors
Exactly because they didn't think they'd get caught
And then for a long time after they did get caught
Their response was always the same 9 11
Hmm
Yeah, that's all they have to say they go before congress. They say 9 11
It's like, yeah, you know what that wears thin after a while
The constitution gives me rights. You're violating my rights
And I want my rights back
Tell me if nsa
Wasn't spying on americans or was spying on americans incidentally to spying operations on foreign nationals
Why do they need a new facility in the utah desert?
That has enough computer memory
to
hold
Every call
Every voicemail every text message from every american for the next 500 years. I am not exaggerated
Look it up
500 years. Why why do they need our data?
You know and why you're it's all fear. It is it's all fear base again
They just go they testify before congress. They say 9 11
Can't have another 9 11
Well americans didn't do 9 11
Why are you spying on americans?
So what you've seen in
You know from your own whistleblower experience
Um, obviously you feel as strongly as I do I feel the same about Edward Snowden
Um, what do you think the chances are you know, because I'm labeled a conspiracy theorist or people in my
My lane are labeled a conspiracy theorist because our argument is is that I believe David grush that he you know
That there has been a long-running
UAP crash retrieval reverse engineering program. I tend to believe him and the other whistleblowers
Do you think it's possible that this could have happened that it is true that there is a retrieval program?
I do
I think we would be fools if we didn't have a retrieval program
And of course because of its very nature it would have to be classified at the very highest levels
You know even at the cia I my last job at the cia was I was the uh the executive assistant to the deputy director
so
I had literally the highest clearances
And I got to see literally everything that the cia was doing everywhere in the world
I did not have access to what you're talking about
But similarly I did not have a q clearance
Which is the clearance necessary to um to be read into nuclear
And nuclear policy issues
So you can be at the very top of the security clearance food chain and still not have access to uap information
You know that it's out there. You know that the program exists. You know that it is tightly
compartmentalized as it should be
But then at the same time there's a big difference
Between acknowledging the existence of a program and releasing the details of the program
Nobody's asking the government to release the details
Just put our minds at ease that we're not crazy when we see these things in the sky
You know and then you say no you didn't you didn't see anything
There is no such thing
You know look over here. Let's talk about this instead
At least acknowledge that it's happening
It seems like the biggest argument or the best argument is that it's uh
National security, you know, we we would give up our our own advantage
We would give up vulnerabilities
Into our own systems if they release this
Do you think there's any validity to the argument that they should keep this secret based on national security?
No, and i'll tell you why
uh until
Until the late 1980s
I'm sorry the late 1970s the the federal government did not even acknowledge the existence of something called nsa
Okay, until the 1990s
The british government did not
Uh admitted the existence of their version of ns state gchq
Okay, now big revelation. We have this thing called nsa
Who cares nobody cares
We didn't ask to be told all of nsa's secrets
We just want to know does nsa exist. Yes, it exists. Okay. Thank you very much. I'm going to go about my business
so
UAPs do they exist? Yes. Okay. Thank you now. I'm going to go about my business
I didn't ask you to explain to me what the science was
I didn't ask ask for you to to let me into the
Hanger where you have the pieces of the vehicles that that crashed
I just want to know that i'm you know
Where my tax dollars are going
And to make sure that you guys are at work to try to keep me safe
No secrets have been spilled
It doesn't damage the national security in any way to acknowledge the existence of such a program
What do you think is the best way to to get this information out? Do you think it is?
Through whistleblowers. Well, is that where it'll come from?
You know, that's that's probably the most satisfying
Because you're going to get more information from whistleblowers than you would for many
from many
Approved press release, let's say
But then the whistleblower puts himself at risk at legal risk mostly
um
So the answer is yes and no yes in that if it weren't for whistleblowers
We wouldn't know half of what we know right now about things like torture and warrantless surveillance and
UAPs and such
But then at the same time
I think we would all like for it to be official
Yeah, I I hate having to argue with people. Well, this whistleblower said that well
This whistleblower said the other thing. Well, I know that other whistleblower and that person's meant to leal
And they've been saying this, you know on 4chan for the last 10 years. Okay. Let's let's make it official
Just an acknowledgement not asking for secrets here. Just tell us where our tax money is going
Are you guys on this case?
We'll see if we can get it maybe this year
I've seen a lot of uh, I sure hope so
I'll tell you the very the one and only thing
That I liked about hillary clinton
Literally the only thing
Was that in the 2016 election? She said that if elected president she would release all this information
And really it was john pedestal her campaign manager
Who had the fascination with it and who talked her into
Staking out that position
I hope donald trump feels the same way
because I think it's high time that
We know as john mccainstead what the government is doing in our name
That's interesting. You said that as well because um ross cultard talked with him. He said that was
a big
Argument or or he I don't know if he believed it or at least it was one argument is that
They were setting up disclosure to be under hillary clinton like she was going to be
The disclosure president so they had set up all these things in order to make it
So that she would actually disclose the information and then she lost
And so they had to shut everything down that that basically stopped the process
of disclosure
So it's interesting exactly right
And like I say it's john pedestal and it's my understanding that john pedestal
Saw something in the sky at some point and has been fascinated by it ever since and he's the one who talked her into doing it
Yeah, so look at it this way too. The structure is there
So that if donald trump
Wants to release it. It can be released rather quickly
But I you probably know better than I I don't know if he's ever taken a position on these things
I've I've released a few videos on him and immediately lost subscribers
You know anytime you talk about these politics going on it's amazing even when they're talking about
Disclosure and transparency
Uh, immediately lose subscribers. So he said he doesn't
Uh, believe that there's
Necessarily ufo's but he does believe that the pilot saw something
So he kind of gives your your standard mainstream. Okay vague vague response is what I've what I've seen from him actually
Okay, well
I don't know maybe
Pete Hexeth has seen something
Maybe Marco Rubio. Maybe I don't know. I hope so. Yeah, definitely the people he has in his cabinet
Like Marco Rubio was surely briefed by many members or many whistleblowers. I'm sure jake barber
Briefed Marco Rubio and his team as well as other people
So I think we're in the best position. I've seen at least the government in
As of late and it's interesting too because I I never I've never seen anything
Um anomalous, right?
You know that I can say definitely not when I was flying as a as a fighter pilot
And I didn't even think about it as a fighter pilot
But I believe people such as yourself, right that you obviously have integrity. I think you've you've shown that in the past
You know, why would you why would you lie about this sighting? You know that you saw
Many years ago and I think there's so many thousands of people
Such as yourself that are we going to believe people like you or people that we know are we going to believe
Uh a security state which obviously has a lot of interest in keeping this this stuff secret and as
Shown in the past that they will
break the law or go against the constitution
to I guess
Save their own skins or
have less
Risk if you will in your casa the internet never stops neither does optimum
While 5g home internet slows down when your vecinos log on optimum keeps going. Bueno famously fast fiber internet bonito whole home coverage
Every rincón barato smart value your family will love get optimum fiber internet for only 30 dollars a month with a five-year price lock
Bueno bonito barato three words your family already knows don't settle go 3b with optimum call 888 for optimum
Or visit optimum.com slash 3b to switch today terms applies the optimum.com for details
Yes, I think that's right on on cia declassified, which you generously agreed to appear on. Um
We talked also about
a recent sighting
Around lake michigan on both sides of lake michigan
Where most of the people reporting the sightings were meteorologists that not only could they see these
Things whatever they were flying in the sky and going down
Into the water and coming back up again, but they were able to track them on radar
And then when the military comes out and says
It's not us. We don't know what the heck it is, but we're seeing it on the radar too
Well, then it kind of leads to questions, doesn't it?
And then the radar tapes disappear when you ask about later exactly
Exactly
So interesting. Um, yeah, why don't we
Uh, finally, let's talk about your cia declassified show. I have a little teaser of uh, the show
I was actually on so why don't I play a little bit of that right now?
great
My whole career in the air force. I was trained as a scientist at university. I went to yusafa. I was a material scientist
And so I never thought any of this stuff was possible
And I kind of just casually looked into it, you know, just saying oh, well that that can't be correct
You know it's that must be crazy right
But the more you look into it it is there is an amazing amount of of information. There's an amazing amount of cases
I hadn't actually even heard of that case. Um, but it doesn't surprise me
It doesn't surprise me at all once you start looking into this
What should we expect to see next especially at the pentagon?
Should we expect more transparency now that they've begun actually speaking about this?
Uh in an unclassified venue or do you think this was a one-shot deal where a couple of years ago
They said okay, we're going to release these videos. We're going to lease release some redacted reports and then that's the end of it
Well, I think they they didn't even really release those original videos. You know, they were leaked luals ando essentially
Leaked them. That's a good point. Even though they're they're unclassified
There's nothing classified in any of those videos that they released, you know
And if you look they'll release countless videos of war of us blowing up
You know some building as soon as
If it's pro propaganda
Then they have no problem releasing these videos of targeting pod images, you know of f-16s or other aircraft
Hitting targets blowing up and killing people on the ground
But then if it comes to these videos all of a sudden now, they can't release them, you know too hard to release
So those videos were were actually leaked
And then the only ones that we have gotten like I said, aren't the ones who we're really asking for which is nimitz
Gimbal those are the ones, you know, what about what about those analysis? So it has come
At tooth and nail the government has fought tooth and nail
Against this pretty much every step of the way and when I say the government I really mean
I really mean the the the military industrial complex the bureaucracy
So that would be the the career bureaucrats the career
People in organizations like the c.a. I'm sorry. I've pointed a lot of fingers at the c.a. But I do too
Also the
Also the pentagon. So really the heroes in this whole thing have been the congressmen and women
Okay, so, uh, yeah, thanks for having me on the show you you a it was fun
Y tv unified tv. It's unif yd unified tv
It is an online tv network a subscription network, but they have dozens of shows
Lots and lots of documentaries and they address issues like the one that we're talking about
It's been a lot of fun. C.i.d classified
Is a show where we take
We take historical issues
and we use the actual
Classified c.i.d documents that have been declassified
Uh to explain these historical issues think of
Think of say the the iran coup of 1953 the chile coup of 1973 the murder of
journalist george polk in uh, thassaloniki greece
mk ultra mk chikwit these these
Experimentation programs using lsd or mind control all these these things that have been talked about for so many years
We we take the original documents and go over them and now in season two
We're also interviewing interesting people like you who have far deeper background on these issues than than i do
So it's been it's been good season one was a success
We even tightened it up and made it more professional looking in season two
And I think people would enjoy it
I just published a board actually haven't published it yet just recorded a video
um talking about the jfk files release and there's this alleged memo that jfk allegedly sent
Uh to the director of the cia mcconn at the time
Um asking for all of the ufo files
But unfortunately they they've been unable to find a second copy of this or any sort of copy of this
Memo all they all they have to go on is this one author lester who says that there was a foyer request
Have you looked into the jfk files release at all or or the assassination?
I've written i've written quite a bit about it. Um
I i'm i'm making an educated guess
in my writing that
uh these
Files that will be released soon
In the next 60 days will not be revelatory. They will probably
Show information
About cia surveillance operations in mexico city in october and november of 1963
I think that pretty much everything that's going to be released about jfk has been released keep in mind that in the early 1970s
uh cia director
Helms destroyed a lot of documents
Which was illegal, but they destroyed a lot of documents. And so I think that
Whatever is left for the most part has been released
That the new 10 or 15 000 pages of documents are going to be documents mostly that have already been released
But with fewer redactions
Um, so we're not going to see a revelation
We could see a revelation
With the release of the rfk documents. Okay, and in my view, that's the more interesting
Trunch that we should expect
for a couple of reasons
sir han sir han
Who was convicted of murdering bobby kennedy?
uh
held a revolver with
seven shots
eight bullets were recovered
And a forensic uh examination in 1993 found that there were between 10 and 13 shots fired
So
Where'd the rest come from?
thomas negucci who was the los angeles county coroner at the time and his world famous
Uh said that the kill shot came from behind kennedy
to the
back of the neck
From a distance of one to three inches
But sir han was in front of kennedy
So where did that shot come from?
There's also a video
showing um a security guard
That night named cesar
Uh
Who hated kennedy and had written anti kennedy?
um screeds
Because this man was was a racist a bigot and he he he said that kennedy would turn the country over to the
Commies and the colors like his brother had
And so there's a video of him in the background
pulling a gun out of his waistband
And you hear bang bang bang bang bang bang and he puts the gun back in
Well in the late 1980s, he's dead now, but in the late 1980s
uh a national geographic channel
1990s a national geographic channel
interviewer
Interviewed him and said did you kill robert kennedy and he said no i was going to
But that arab fella got him first
Well, he was polygraphed by the fbi as part of the investigation and he passed the polygraph
So
Where did those extra shots come from?
It may be
Finally we'll get an answer to to that question or to others surrounding the kennedy assassination
And then the martin luther king documents are going to be released at the same time
There's credible evidence that the fbi, you know may have had something to do with that killing
The fbi tried to get king to commit suicide three years earlier. They sent him an anonymous letter
Urging him to kill himself
Does that work? I guess never never
We'll send him a letter. What if we can talk him into killing himself?
yeah
wow, so
You know james url ray who was convicted of killing him
uh
Was drunk
Was in the bathroom of a rooming house a block away
Sat in the bathroom all day long until he saw king and then took that shot from a block away drunk
Come on
So there's there's are some incredible
Um
Incredible accusations out there that the fbi was involved and then martin luther king the third his eldest son
Said publicly that he never believed james url ray killed his father
And he went to prison multiple times and met with james url ray
Martin luther king the third believed that the fbi killed his father
And the fbi had already murdered fred hampton they executed fred hampton in cold blood while he was sleeping
No less they shot him in the head while he was asleep in bed
Because they were so fearful of that you know that black
savior
in the 1960s
Yeah, it seems like it all comes from fear all these um
All these terrible deeds. Yes
Yes, it's fear
So what has been from doing the show from your experience in cia?
um
Being a whistleblower what's been the most I guess um shocking
thing that you've learned from about uap's specifically or I guess most enlightening
thing you've encountered
You know
There was nothing that I learned while I was at the cia
It's once I got out of the cia that I began really learning about this stuff by watching people like you for example
You know, it's it's nice to know that there are others out there who
Believe there are others out there who have seen things themselves who are not lunatics
Right, the when this information was was leaked
What was it a couple of years ago from the pentagon showing video for example?
And and and the audio pilot to pilot audio saying things like are you seeing this?
Look at how fast it's going
It makes me realize
That no, no, there's something out there that we just don't understand
The government wants us to think that we're crazy or that our eyes are playing tricks on us
Or we're not seeing what we think we're seeing it's something that's easily explainable. It's not
Let's just be honest about it
I don't understand why there's such pushback against honesty and about and and transparency
We should be transparent about this
So it's been the last couple of years have been particularly exciting in this area
Yeah, I totally completely agree. It really has been exciting and it's great to see people such as yourself out there john
I mean, I really think integrity is is is all we really have to stand on
And yeah, I really admire. I really admire your courage and thanks for speaking out now
Thank you
Say for everybody in the audience go check out unify d tv check out cia
Declassified think will all be in the descriptions for everything john does
And uh, yeah, please like this video and share it to get the information out
And subscribe and go to patreon.com forward slash chris lato if you want to support my work
So thanks again, john. Have a great rest of your day. Thank you chris. Same to you
In your casa the internet never stops neither does optimum while 5g home internet slows down when your vecinos log on
Optimum keeps going bueno famously fast fiber internet bonito whole home coverage every rincón barato
Smart value your family will love get optimum fiber internet for only $30 a month with a five-year price lock bueno bonito barato
Three words your family already knows don't settle go 3b with optimum collate 884 optimum or visit optimum.com slash 3b to switch today
Terms applies the optimum.com for details